

Computer Vision Researcher

Roles: Researcher, Supervisor, Lecturer, Invited speaker, Engineer.

Email: Silvia[dot]Laura[dot]Pintea[at]gmail[dot]com

Webpage: http://silvialaurapintea.github.io

My work in Computer Vision has been focused on: motion analysis extended to medical applications in collaboration with Leiden University Medical Center, and regression problems, also combined with the use of Deep Learning. I am now looking into using Computer Vision knowledge to make Deep Networks more training-time efficient and thus more environmental friendly.

EDUCATION

PhD	Computer Vision
Institution	University van Amsterdam Amsterdam, NL
Period	2011 - 2016
Thesis Title	Continuous Learning in Computer Vision
Focus	Motion prediction, object localization, video representation learning
\mathbf{MSc}	Artificial Intelligence
Institution	University van Amsterdam Amsterdam, NL
Period /Avg. Grade	$2009 - 2011 \mid 8.31 \text{ (out of } 10)$
Focus	Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Neural Networks, Game Theory.
\mathbf{BSc}	Computer Science
Institution	University of Bucharest, Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science, Bucharest, RO
Period /Avg. grade	$2005 - 2008 \mid 9.40 \text{ (out of } 10)$
Focus	Algorithms and data structures, Object oriented programming, Formal methods.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Professor	Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology, Delft, NL
(Tenure Track)	Focus on Deep Learning efficiency
Period	July 2020 — Present

$\mathbf{PostDoc}$	Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology, Delft, NL
Period	July 2018 — July 2020
Job Description	Geophysical seismic image analysis with the use of Deep Learning.
$\mathbf{PostDoc}$	Vision Lab, Delft University of Technology, Delft, NL
Period	July 2016 — July 2018
Job Description	Working on the "Technology in Motion" project with the Leiden University Medical Center towards diagnosing and treatment of motor diseases. Project link: https://tim.lumc.nl
R&D Engineer	Layar/Blippar, Amsterdam, NL
Period	January — June 2016
Job Description	Adding state-of-the-art Deep Learning methods for large-scale image retrieval, feature match-

KEY PUBLICATIONS

"Deep hough-transform line priors.", Y Lin, SL Pintea, JC van Gemert, European Conference on Computer Vision, 2020.

ing and binarization algorithms.

"Asymmetric kernels in Gaussian Process for learning target variance.", SL Pintea, JC van Gemert, AWM Smeulders, Pattern Recognition Letters, 2018

"Video Acceleration Magnification". "CONFERENCE, Y Zhang, SL Pintea, JC van Gemert, Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2017 (https://acceleration-magnification.github.io)

"Déjà Vu: Motion Prediction in Static Images.", SL Pintea, JC van Gemert, AWM Smeulders, European Conference on Computer Vision, 2014, (http://github.com/SilviaLauraPintea/DejaVu)

Complete list of publications: Google Scholar

Additional Information

Reviewer CVPR, ECCV/ICCV, BMVC, ICPR, ICML, NeurIPS, TIP, IJCV Conference participation International participation: CVPR 2021, ICCV 2021, ECCV 2020, ICIP 2018, ICIP 2016, workshop ECCV 2016, ECCV 2014 Local participation: NCCV 2019, NCCV 2018, ICT.Open 2016, ICT.Open 2012 NVPHBV 2017, Nuctech meeting Delft, Delft-Leiden Deep Learning Seminars Invited speaker 2019. Deep Learning MSc course TUDelft Invited lecturer BSc Image Processing course, MSc Computer Vision course at TUDelft Lecturer TEACHING ASSISTANT BSc Short Course on Pattern Recognition, MSc Computer Vision course. MSC SUPERVISOR Tobias Stahl, Yichao Zhang, Chengqiu Zhang, Xilin Li, Yue Liu, Omar Hommos, Xiaoming Wen, Jian Zheng, Ziyu Bao, Yordan Dimitrov, Nikhil Saldanha. PhD supervisor Vedran Vukotic, Abolfazi Nadi, Yancong Lin, Xin Liu. Outstanding Reviewer award CVPR 2021, Best paper award for the Workshop AWARD on Hands, ECCV 2018. Languages & Tools Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow, C/C++, Caffe, Torch, PHP, Java, OpenCV, Dlib, Shogun, LibSVM, VlFeat, Yael, Cuda-Convnet, Matlab. References $Dr. \ Arnold \ Smeulders \ (A[dot]W[dot]M[dot]Smeulders[at]uva[dot]nl)$

 $Dr. \ Marco \ Loog \ (M[dot]Loog[at]tudelft[dot]nl)$

Dr. Jan van Gemert (J[dot]C[dot]vanGemert[at]tudelft[dot]nl)